TONY BUMATAY

tony.bumatay@wustl.edu

SUMMARY

Computer Science and Entrepreneurship double major passionate about solving challenging technological problems with business applications. Extensive experience as a strong leader, team member, and communicator. Proven problem solver with the ability to adapt to a fast-paced entrepreneurial environment evidenced by work on an Agile software development team at Duke Manufacturing.

EDUCATION

WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY IN ST. LOUIS, SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING AND APPLIED SCIENCES

St. Louis, MO
May 2017

Bachelor of Science

Majors in Computer Science and Entrepreneurship

Overall GPA: 3.51/4.00

FUNDAÇÃO GETULIO VARGAS

São Paulo, Brazil

International Program in Management

July-December 2015

• Adapted quickly to a foreign environment and embraced cultural differences. Connected with people of diverse backgrounds

RELEVANT COURSES

Object-Oriented Software Dev. – Rapid Prototype Dev. & Creative Programming – Mobile App Development Cloud Computing with Big Data Applications — Algorithms and Data Structures – Technology Entrepreneurship

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, C++, PHP, Swift, Python, HTML, CSS, JS, Symfony, R, MySQL, Xcode, Firebase, Hadoop, MapReduce, Hive, Spark, Linux

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

DUKE MANUFACTURING COMPANY

St. Louis, MO

Duke Visor Software Engineering Intern

May - July 2015

- Embraced Agile software development culture and the Visor team's fast-paced, entrepreneurial environment
- Utilized Symfony PHP framework in full-stack, pre-launch development of an integrated web app for high profile client
- Successfully pitched a proposal to the VP of Software Systems on incorporating the R statistical engine into Visor software
- Integrated R scripts with SQL queries to create data visualizations leading to valuable insights from customer data

TEACHING ASSISTANT - WEBSITE DEVELOPMENT

Spring 2015/16

• Facilitated student growth in in-class and one-on-one settings, graded assignments, and communicated personalized feedback

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

CAMP OWATONNA

Harrison, ME

Head of Counselor in Training Leadership Program

June - August 2016

- Crafted and led a 7-week leadership training program, which demanded improved teamwork, leadership ability, initiative, and character growth from all fifteen 16-year old boys
- Planned and executed a 20-person, six day wilderness expedition to the remote Allagash Wilderness in Northern Maine
- Demonstrated strong interpersonal communication and collaboration skills, working closely with a broad range of colleagues from the Camp Director and Executive Director to the enrolled 16 year-old boys on a daily basis

Cabin Counselor and Team Sports/Waterskiing Instructor

Summer 2012 – Summer 2014

- Created and communicated weekly objectives in character development, observed the campers' progress, provided feedback for improvement, and relayed assessments to the Camp Director
- · Honed mediation and listening skills, problem solving abilities, and improvisation tactics as one of four Division Leaders

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY MEN'S CLUB ULTIMATE FRISBEE

St. Louis, MO

Captain

May 2016 - Present

- Collaborate with co-captains and coaches to analyze team needs and plan 3 weekly practices to improve on weaknesses
- Lead peers on and off the field, maintain a cohesive dynamic for 30 diverse men, and challenge each to continuously improve
- Collaborate with Treasurer to manage logistics for 7-8 annual weekend tournaments

Webmaster

May 2014 - Present

• Took initiative to construct and maintain a custom, responsive website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Indoor Ultimate Championships: Sectional Tournament Director

November 2014-January 2015

Planned and coordinated the tournament, collaborated with the IUC Director, recruited teams, and managed logistics

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Personal Interests: Hiking/Backpacking, Traveling, Ultimate Frisbee, Soccer, Photography
- · Languages: Conversational in Spanish and Portuguese